Olawole Ogunfunminiyi frankfurtmacmoses@gmail.com +1(832) 8150073

PROFILE / SUMMARY

Frankfurt is an experience and a business minded software engineer, data scientist and Project Manager; able to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advance data driving methods, willing to experiment with custom algorithms and ideals for business applications and data products.

EXPERTISE

- Data mugging / cleaning and Descriptive
 Analysis with R tidyverse and other R packages
- Big Data Queries and Interpretation with Hive
- Machine Learning Algorithms with R and Python
 sklearn, pandas, NumPy and R caret package
- Reproducible Research and Report Generation with R
- Data visualization with R ggplot2 and python ggplot implementation

- Data Driving Application with Oracle Apex
- Oracle Weblogic and Glassfish server configurations for Oracle apex 5.1 and other JEE applications
- Extensive knowledge of Linux operating system commands and scripting
- Versatile with object-oriented design/programming with java/Python
- Knowledge of Business component development with JEE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Projects/Products Consultant Osun State Government/Word Bank, Nigeria

April 2014 – Dec. 2018

- Delivered the approved project chatter and project management plan for building 195 megawatts electricity to power the state secretariat to be financed by Exim bank, U.S.A between 2014-2017.
- Project Managed the team responsible for design of Big Data Analytics usage for strategic repositioning of Bureau of Social Services (BOSS) for effective Monitoring and Evaluation of government's projects to support effective budgeting by Ministry of Finance and Economic Planning.
- Review proposals from service providers of application automation to government and scheduling products that ensure core business
 processes run faster, more accurately and without interruption.
- Drafted operation processes for submitting reports and made presentations in conjunction with Ministry of Information, Science and Technology to review usage of bulk Microsoft licenses procured by the State Government of Osun.
- Developed intricate algorithms based on deep-dive statistical analysis and predictive data modeling that were used to deepen relationships, strengthen longevity and personalize interactions with customers.
- Analyzed and processed complex data sets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Identified, measured and recommended improvement strategies for KPIs across all business areas.
- Responsible for parsing and merging datasets
- Directly involved information technology training for the Youth Employment and Social Support Operations (YESSO) activities of the World Bank / Osun State Government
- Trained R and Python Programmers regarding applicable regulatory guidelines and programming activities for the other supporting team in Monitoring and Evaluation department of YESSO project.

Software Developer

February 2012 – January 2014

MTN Nigeria

- Worked with the, business analysis, testers and project manager.
- Involved in logical modeling and physical modeling of application.
- Developed Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages and SQL Scripts using Oracle PL/SQL.
- Involved in creation of Conceptual Modeling covering all the business requirements.
- Loaded the data into database tables using SQL*loader from text and excel files.

- Developed data model, SQL Queries, SQL Query tuning process and Schemas.
- Created SQL*plus reports as per client's various needs, and developed business objects.
- Developed SQL scripts for Referential Integrity check, which checks validity of incoming data with master tables in database.
- Involved in updating procedures, functions, triggers, and packages for validation and loading of data into target table based on the current requirement.
- Utilized Struts2, Spring MVC and HibernateJPAframework for development
- Involved in Design Development and Implementation of business Applications using Java/J2EE Technologies.

Operations/Quality Assurance Manager

ChamsSwitch Limited (a subsidiary of Chams Plc)

Sept 2006 - Nov. 2011

- Managed a 10-man team to develop web applications to extend the functionality of Base24 Switch.
- Designed and supervised the implementation of installation of Ivery web payment gateway 5 weeks before the deadline.
- Supervised step-by-step connection of many merchants to Ivery web payment gateway and bank ATMs to Base24 Switch before the establishment of Nigeria Central Switch.
- Supervised the activities of junior staff including work allocation, training and conflict resolution.
- Responsible for managing activities of software developers for testing and integration of revenue collection application (Paycollect) to banking applications of head offices of 15 Nigeria Banks within 8 months.

Senior Instructor

New Horizons Computer Learning Centre, Nigeria

June 2006 – November 2008

- Team Leader, and Senior Instructor New Horizons / Babcock University joint program. Taught Object Oriented programming and SQLServer in Babcock University.
- Developed application on Microsoft Dot Net Platform: Test Engine for Students Performance Evaluation using Microsoft.Net 2.0 Platform with Microsoft SQLServer.
- Project Management Team and Co Developer for E-learning Application for Nigeria Bottling Company (NBC) and FCMB.
- Trained corporate organizations: Con-Oil Plc, Diamond, Bank First Bank Plc, EFCC etc in JAVA, XML, VB.NET, SQL SERVER, PL/SQL and ASP.NET

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION:

Graduate Diploma Computer Science – Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria

2017

Thesis Title: Comparative analysis of Pig and Hive

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business School Netherlands

2015

Thesis Title: Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics In Osun State, Nigeria BSC Soil Science – Obafemi Awolowo University – Nigeria 2003

CERTIFICATIONS

2008 Project Management Professional, PMP (ID: 1212004)

Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java EE 1.4 Platform (SCWCD) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated Sun Certified Programmer for Java Platform (1.4) (SCJP) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated, Now Oracle Incorporation

2006 Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) Awarded by Oracle Incorporation

John Hopkins University Bloomberg School of Public Health Verified Certificate - Coursera

Data Science Toolbox Getting and Cleaning Data R Programming Exploratory Data Analysis Statistical Inference Regression Model Reproducible Research

University of California, San Diego, Verified Certificate - Coursera

Introduction to Big Data Analytics

Hadoop Platform and Application Framework

Introduction to Big Data